Cristian López Solá

<u>cristianlopezc4@gmail.com</u> | <u>GitHub</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u> | Lleida, Spain

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Experienced working with teams to produce impactful, leading-edge websites that engage customers and deliver business results. Well-versed in design standards and user preferences. Possesses knowledge of Angular with ability to quickly learn new technologies. Demonstrated success in identifying and resolving code issues.

SKILLS

Programming skills: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Typescript, ASP.NET, SQL, npm, Java, NodeJS

Frameworks: AngularJS, Angular2+

Software skills: Git, GitHub, GitLab, Figma, Azure DevOps

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NBX Digital - Frontend Developer (November 2023 – March 2024)

- Refactor legacy code using new methods supported by the latest versions of JavaScript.
- Replace all unsupported libraries with current ones and develop directives as needed.
- Research and correct libraries with disproportionate sizes, replacing them with more appropriate ones using Webpack Bundle Analyzer.
- Develop and design new screens using CSS Flexbox and CSS Grid, following Figma patterns.
- Create reusable Angular libraries for services, components, styles, and icons, and automate packaging using Azure DevOps pipelines to publish them to a private npm feed.
- Develop the Docker file for the frontend application, considering files like Nginx and npm registry, to test the application using custom endpoints.

GFT Technologies - Frontend Developer (January 2022 – November 2023)

- Migration of applications to latest versions of Angular.
- Add, create, edit columns in the database from the backend through JDBC Java class.
- Improved the application using Stencil, which is a design system based in web components.
- Collaborated in the change of the authorization method to log into the application, the backend proxy and the backend environment.
- Use of the TypeScript (Angular 13) and JavaScript (AngularJS) to make some changes to the current logic of the application to adapt the new functionalities such as the grids, the overlays, the search engines, the forms.
- Developed new screens with RxJS.
- Research and resolution of incidents affecting the application, with their respective solutions on the frontend when applicable.
- Collaborated with stakeholders during development processes to confirm creative proposals and design best practices.
- Designed and updated layouts to meet usability and performance requirements.
- Developed validation improvements for all the forms.
- Analyzed the response time between the application, FireBase and Google Cloud.
- Analysed and improved the execution of Google Cloud Funtions with NodeJS.

GFT Technologies – Production Support Analyst (January 2018 – December 2021)

GFT Technologies – Software Developer (September 2017 – December 2017)

• Developed new features using MVC architecture.

CERTIFICATIONS

- o Professional Foundations of Project Management, by Microsoft and LinkedIn, MICROSOFT
- o Professional Foundations of Software Development, by Microsoft and LinkedIn, MICROSOFT
- o IT Specialist Software Development, **CERTIPORT**
- o Angular Testing Masterclass (w/ Angular 16), UDEMY
- o B2 First (FCE), Cambridge University Press & Assessment

EDUCATION

ILERNA FP, Certificate of Higher Education in Web Development (September 2015 - June 2017)